battlestarwiki.org 2019-06-27

# Battlestar Wiki:Privacy policy - Battlestar Wiki

From Battlestar Wiki, the free, open content Battlestar Galactica encyclopedia and episode guide

|  |   
---|---|---  
|  | **This page is anofficial policy of _Battlestar Wiki_.**  
This policy is considered by the community and its leadership to be the status quo of _Battlestar Wiki_ and is not to be countermanded or ignored, though changes to it can be discussed on the appropriate talk page. This policy was implemented on 21 September 2007.  |   
---|---|---  
|  |   
  
## Privacy Policy - Commitment to your privacy

This site is owned and operated by _Battlestar Wiki_ and [FrakMedia! Productions](http://www.frakmedia.net/). Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At _Battlestar Wiki_ , we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe. 

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. 

## Information _Battlestar Wiki_ gathers and tracks

### _Battlestar Wiki_ gathers two types of information about users:

  * Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys:
  * Information _Battlestar Wiki_ gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Because _Battlestar Wiki_ derives its revenue mainly from sponsorships and advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. Under no circumstances does _Battlestar Wiki_ divulge any information about an individual user to a third party.

### _Battlestar Wiki_ Gathers User Information In The Following Processes:

**Optional Voluntary Information**

We offer the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users: 

  1. **Wiki/Talk pages** \- Editing users of the site's Wiki and talk pages must register for these services (both are free of charge) in order to post, although they needn't register to visit the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address.
  2. **Electronic newsletters policy (Dispatches)** \- We will offer a free electronic newsletter to users. _Battlestar Wiki_ gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration.
  3. **"E-mail this to a friend" policy** \- Our site users can choose to electronically forward a link, page, or documents to someone else by clicking "e-mail this to a friend". The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose.
  4. **Polling** \- We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. _Battlestar Wiki_ may use a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users.
  5. **Surveys** \- _Battlestar Wiki_ may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.

**Children**

Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 

**Usage tracking**

_Battlestar Wiki_ tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. _Battlestar Wiki_ does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser). 

_Battlestar Wiki_ sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. 

**Cookies**

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. _Battlestar Wiki_ uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). Our advertising system delivers a one-time cookie to better track ad impressions and click rates. 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in the Wiki, message boards, polling and surveys. 

### Use of information

_Battlestar Wiki_ uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. _Battlestar Wiki_ never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. 

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. 

Stats trackers that we use to gather data include [AWstats](http://awstats.sourceforge.net/), [Quantcast](http://www.quantcast.com/), and [Woopra](http://www.woopra.com/). Woopra is the only live stats tracking software installed, where we can look up where you are on the site. If you wish not to be tracked, you should log out, however this will prevent you from editing article pages. This information can only be seen by members of the [FrakMedia! Productions](http://www.frakmedia.net/) team. In **no way** is this information given out to anyone. 

Woopra allows us to analyze our site better to help you navigate this wiki. To learn more about Woopra, please visit their website. 

### Sharing of the information

_Battlestar Wiki_ uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs. This is essential to keeping our service free. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

### Security

_Battlestar Wiki_ operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers. 

### Opt-out policy

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include: 

  * Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users.

### Your consent

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by _Battlestar Wiki_. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
